BIDA MOHAMED AMINE

Senior Full-Stack Developer



OVERVIEW

Senior full-stack developer with more than 9 years of hands-on experience developing, designing, and implementing scalable web applications and internal tools that drastically improve efficiency in state and private companies, these years have allowed me to evolve and advance in the field of IT. The chance to work in a large company ensures the continuity of professional training, which help me be up to date with new technologies, and to practice them on site, either by building managements applications or web solutions. Finding, proposing and implementing solutions in the context of carrying out my work is my complete satisfaction. Seeking to broad development leverage experience and hands-on technical expertise in a challenging role as a Fullstack Developer



LANGUAGES

Arabic (Native)

French (Intermediate)

English (Intermediate)





QUALITIES

Professional skills

Frontend (React, NextJS)
Backend (NodeJS, Express)
SQL Databases (MySQL)
NoSQL Database(MongoDB)
Mobile development (Flutter)
Dot NET Development (C#)

Personal qualities

Initiative
Organized and rigorous
Communication
Great availability
Sense of analysis







EXPERIENCE

Head of Informatics Department

ALGIERS Sep **2021 - to date**

Main IT Project Manager

ALGIERS Nov **2015** - Sep **2021**

VCL

ENCC. - Subsidiary of the **IMETAL Group**Ensures the organization, monitoring and implementation of all the company's software, ERP system and IT infrastructure, manages the IT department's budget and defines the quality and security procedures of the information systems

+213 560 47 24 26

mohamedamine.bida@gmail.com

Si Mustapha, Boumerdes, 35028 ALGERIE

https://moumouh206.github.io/

Project ENCC. - Subsidiary of the IMETAL Group

Responsible to work within a team to integrate a software package and develop specific solutions tailored to the demand of internal users of the company.

Recent projects:

- Development of fully functioning ERP System
- Design, architecture and construction of the enterprise data center.
- Unify the business tools of the units.
- Create a digital security solution for all units.
- Centralization of unit databases.
- Development of corporate unit different websites.

FullStack Developer

ALGIERS May **2012** - Nov **2015**

ALIECO SPA unit of **ENCC Company**

- Development of more than 23+ full-stack business applications on various platforms using the latest techniques and frameworks adopted by industry for web and desktop and ensured safety and integration capacity with multiple APIs and databases
- Developed full-stack web applications to manage the data collected which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications and software with complete accuracy.



EDUCATION

Master's degree

BOUMERDES **2009 - 2011**

Bachelor's degree

BOUMERDES **2006 - 2009**

Google's Certificate

Online Sep **21-In Progress**

M'hamed Bougara University of Boumerdes

Master 2 in Distributed Computer Systems (Sep 2011) equivalent to Master - Second cycle university studies, research topic: "Modeling and testing of flash memory performance in AADL language".

M'hamed Bougara University of Boumerdes

License in Infotronic (electronics informatic) (June 2009) equivalent to specialized baccalaureate of 3 years. Research topic: "Study of encryption methods for television channels".

Google Career Certificates

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate I already completed 2 of 8 courses

BIDA MOHAMED AMINE

Développeur Senior Full-Stack



OVERVIEW

Développeur senior full-stack avec plus de 9 ans d'expérience pratique dans la conception, le développement et la mise en œuvre d'applications Web évolutives et d'outils internes qui améliorent considérablement l'efficacité des entreprises publiques et privées, ces années m'ont permis d'évoluer et d'avancer dans le domaine du système d'information. La chance de travailler dans une grande entreprise assure la continuité de la formation professionnelle, ce qui m'aide à être à jour avec les nouvelles technologies, et à les pratiquer sur place, que ce soit dans les applications de gestion d'immeubles et les solutions web. Trouver, proposer et mettre en œuvre des solutions dans le cadre de la réalisation de mon travail est mon entière satisfaction. Cherchant à tirer parti d'une vaste expérience en développement et d'une expertise technique pratique dans un rôle stimulant en tant que développeur fullstack



LANGUAGES

Arab (Native)

Français (Intermédiate)

Anglais (Intermédiate)



QUALITIES

Qualités professionnelles

Frontend (React, NextJS)
Backend (NodeJS, Express)
SQL BDD (MySQL)
NoSQL BDD (MongoDB)
Mobile (Flutter)



NET (C#)

Initiative
Organisé et rigoureux
Communication
Grande disponibilité
Sens de l'analyse





EXPERIENCE

Chef du département informatique

ALGIERS Sep **2021 - to date**

Chef de projet informatique central

ALGIERS Nov **2015** - Sep **2021**

Développeur Full Stack

ALGIERS Mai 2012-Nov **2015**



ENCC. - Filiale du Groupe IMETAL

Assure l'organisation, le suivi et la mise en place de l'ensemble des logiciels, du système ERP et de l'infrastructure informatique de l'entreprise, gère le budget de la DSI et définit les procédures qualité et sécurité des systèmes d'information

ALGERIE

+213 560 47 24 26

mohamedamine.bida@gmail.co

https://moumouh206.github.io/

Si Mustapha, Boumerdes, 35028

ENCC. - Filiale du Groupe IMETAL

Responsable de travailler au sein d'une équipe pour intégrer un progiciel et développer des solutions spécifiques adaptées à la demande des utilisateurs internes de l'entreprise.

Les projets récents :

- Développement d'un système ERP entièrement fonctionnel
- Conception, architecture et construction de l'entreprise DATA-CENTER.
- Unifier les outils métiers des unités.
- Créer une solution de sécurité numérique pour toutes les unités.
- Centralisation des bases de données unitaires.
- Développement des différents sites web de l'unité corporative

ALIECO SPA unit é de ENCC

- Développement de plus de 23+ applications d'entreprise full-stack sur diverses plates-formes en utilisant les dernières techniques et frameworks adoptés par l'industrie pour le Web et bureau et garantie de la sécurité et de la capacité d'intégration avec plusieurs API et bases de données
- Développement d'applications Web full-stack pour gérer les données collectées qui ont traité, analysé et rendu les données visuellement.
- Gestion des mises à jour urgentes, y compris les modifications de contenu et les mises à niveau de la base de données.
- . Planifié, écrit et débogué des applications Web et des logiciels avec une précision totale.

EDUCATION

Master

BOUMERDES **2009 - 2011**

Licence

BOUMERDES **2006 - 2009**

Certificat de Google

Enligne Sep **21-En cours**

Université M'hamed Bougara de Boumerdès

Master 2 Systèmes Informatiques Répartis (sept. 2011) équivalent au Master - Etudes universitaires de deuxième cycle, sujet de recherche :" Modélisation et test des performances de la mémoire flash en langage AADL".

Université M'hamed Bougara de Boumerdès

Licence en Infotronique (électronique informatique) (juin 2009) équivalant au baccalauréat spécialisé de 3 ans. Sujet de recherche : "Etude des méthodes de cryptage pour les chaînes de télévision".

Google Career Certificates

Certificat professionnel Google Data Analytics J'ai déjà terminé 2 des 8 cours